otherwise I would ask Steve from my era
不然我会问史蒂夫
as one after working group members to
作为工作组成员之后的一个
voice his view of the world it could be
发表他对世界的看法
a long discussion
长时间的讨论
my view is eventually we will drive
我的观点是最终我们会开车
innovation very we will drive innovation
创新，我们将推动创新
by collaborating on api's and that will
通过在api上进行协作，
mean everybody working together and then
意思是每个人一起工作，然后
competing the hell out of each other on
彼此竞争
the run time so my job is to beat these
运行时间，所以我的工作是击败这些
guys run times and performance and
伙计们的时间和表现
operational management things and that
运营管理的东西
combination of collaboration to get
结合获得合作
clean api's to developers and
清洁api给开发人员和
competition on efficiency and product is
在效率和产品上的竞争是
obviously the other thing is the best of
显然，另一件事是最好的
both worlds that's what drove java
推动Java的两个世界
originally i think we can get back to
本来我认为我们可以回到
driving that again in the future and
将来再次推动
limit related to that with the opening
与开头有关的限制
up of all the specifications in the
的所有规格
licensing which as an open-source player
作为开源参与者的许可
that isn't a licensee i'm very happy
那不是被许可人，我很高兴
with all the licenses they're that
与所有的许可证，他们就是
they're very very open I'd hope to see
他们非常非常开放，我希望看到
the new up-and-coming people coming with
新的有前途的人
their challenges really new eight new
他们的挑战真的很新8个新
implementations I hope see ya don't
我希望看到的实现不要
forget what the there hasn't been a lot
忘记那里没有很多
of new vendors entering the the Java EE
进入Java EE的新供应商
marketplace for quite a few years right
相当多年的市场
there is at least the possibility that
至少有可能
by lowering the barriers to entry that
通过降低进入壁垒
we will see other entrants
我们将看到其他参赛者
you take micro for example there are a
你以微为例，有一个
lot of micro profile implementations but
许多微型配置文件的实现，但
like Tonya's here's Wayne's here you've
就像托尼亚（Tonya）在这里，韦恩（Wayne）在这里
got a whole bunch of people from the
有一大堆人从
various committees just because I'm not
只是因为我不是
here doesn't mean that there's there's
这并不意味着那里有
there's probably better answers sitting
坐在那里可能会有更好的答案
here quietly
静静地在这里
didn't mind so but thank you very much
不介意，但非常感谢
for coming and I hope this was helpful
来，我希望这会有所帮助
thank you for coming the questions
谢谢你提出问题
remote I see that a few people dialed in
远程，我看到有人拨了进来
any questions comments nothing yet
任何问题都没有评论
everyone happy great so the bang you are
每个人都很高兴，所以你很高兴
the guy that has to market the hell out
必须把地狱推销出去的人
of of this what we produce all the chaos
这就是我们造成的所有混乱
and and so on what's your take on that
等等，您对此有何看法
I'm leaving with Mike you know I think
我和迈克一起离开，你知道我认为
there's an opportunity for us to
我们有机会
continue to collaborate in fact what we
实际上，我们继续合作
do as a marketing committee you may not
做一个营销委员会，你可能不会
be aware but this is in as much as we
要知道，但这和我们一样
have a steering committee spec committee
有一个指导委员会规格委员会
we also have a marketing committee and
我们也有一个营销委员会，
we get together on a weekly basis to
我们每周聚会
discuss essentially the strategies and
本质上讨论策略并
tactics that will allow us to achieve
使我们能够实现的策略
the goals that that we've agreed upon
我们已经达成的目标
namely first and foremost in alignment
即首先对齐
with the working group goals we want to
我们想要的工作组目标
drive the awareness and adoption of
推动对
technologies we want to engage as they
我们想参与其中的技术
may be we want to position Jakarta EE as
也许我们想将Jakarta EE定位为
as the future of cloud native
作为云原生的未来
application development in an enterprise
企业中的应用程序开发
context so we have some ambitious and
因此我们有一些雄心勃勃的
lofty goals certainly that's that's
远大的目标
something that we we would agree to but
我们会同意的东西，但是
the fact is we're working collectively
事实是我们正在集体工作
together and there's representation from
在一起，有来自
each of the strategic members on that
每个战略成员
marketing committee and you know so far
营销委员会，到目前为止，您知道
so far so good
到现在为止还挺好
I mean I think one of the challenges
我的意思是我认为挑战之一
that we've experienced is that and I
我们经历过的就是我
think as other folks have probably
像其他人一样思考
spoken to I joined late here but
跟我说过话来晚了
as we've been challenged to provide the
因为我们一直面临着提供
necessary updates that that so many
这么多的必要更新
people are hungry for right so we
人们渴望获得权利，所以我们
haven't been able to give news because
未能提供消息，因为
there hasn't been much news but as of
没有太多的新闻，但截至
late you will have seen a number of blog
迟了，您会看到很多博客
come out over the last few days that
在过去的几天里出来
we've been steadily increasing the
我们一直在稳步增加
cadence the frequency with respect to
节奏相对于
the certification of didn't know that
的认证不知道
you also have to oh these are yours on a
您还必须哦，这些是您的
marketing committee anything yes I mean
营销委员会是什么意思
we do meet on a regular basis and just
我们确实定期开会
do what the bank said thank you that
做银行说的谢谢你
yeah so so we have a series of tasks
是的，所以我们有一系列的任务
that we're executing one of them being
我们正在执行其中之一
the blog post for example and among
例如，博客文章以及
other topics I mean there are short term
其他意思是短期
items and long term items Jakarta one
项目和长期项目雅加达一
was another long term item you know what
是另一个长期项目，你知道吗
we're thinking about having a Jakarta
我们正在考虑有一个雅加达
one conference next year but we've
明年有一个会议，但我们已经
postponed that until 2020 so next year
推迟到2020年，所以明年
we're looking at probably having virtual
我们正在寻找可能有虚拟
conferences for Jakarta one and that's
雅加达的一次会议，那就是
just one example of the many things that
只是很多事情的一个例子
we've been talking and discussing during
我们一直在谈论和讨论
the calls which is a community or an
呼叫是社区还是
association of German Java user groups
德国Java用户组协会
the what can Java user group speed the
Java用户组可以怎样加速
German ones or the I guess the
德国的或我猜的
overarching also International Java user
也涵盖了国际Java用户
groups do to help here there are things
团体帮忙这里有些事
we actually planning to do
我们实际上打算做
german-speaking people organizing with
与会讲德语的人
giving foundation background process and
给出基础背景过程和
then a combined session with some
然后结合一些
technical aspects that was in the
在技​​术方面
planning phase and on the community day
规划阶段和社区日
on Monday we had some sort of test run
星期一我们进行了某种测试
of that concept but would be a usual
这个概念，但通常
evening talk let us know if we can do
晚上的谈话让我们知道我们是否可以做
something of course it would nice would
当然这会很好
be nice to have you at our big
很高兴有您加入我们
conference especially and community
特别是会议和社区
event has an official program and
活动有官方程序，
community program which is driven by the
由
Java user groups themselves and there's
Java用户自己进行分组，
a Jakarta AE or a session already
雅加达AE或会议已经
planned and if you have ideas or want to
有计划的，如果您有想法或想要
contribute and I have another question
贡献，我还有另一个问题
regarding the specification process
关于规范过程
Mike mentioned there's way right access
迈克提到了正确的访问方法
to the document how you plan that Google
到文档中，您如何计划该Google
document as code approach do you can
您可以将文件作为代码方法
answer that
回答那个
though I have personal opinions I have
虽然我有个人意见
personal biases but I've no strong
个人偏见，但我并不坚强
opinion other than it is an open source
意见不是开源
project and a hypothetical I guess I
项目和假设我猜我
open source project and that the open
开源项目，并且
source rules of engagement apply which
参与的原始规则适用于
means that the playing field must be
意味着比赛场地必须是
level must be able to actually access it
级别必须能够实际访问它
everyone must be able actually access
每个人都必须能够实际访问
the document must be able to accept
该文件必须能够接受
contributions anybody must be able to
任何人都必须能够做出的贡献
observe the the work being done while
观察正在进行的工作
it's in progress my personal preference
这是我个人的喜好
is something like asciidoc in a git
在git中就像asciidoc一样
repository because that's all right then
仓库，因为那没关系
we're done here
我们在这里完成
no honestly personally personally I find
我没有找到老实的个人
Google Docs are great for initial
Google文档非常适合初学者
collaborations when you're doing like
做事时的合作
really fast-paced collaborative work but
真正快节奏的协作工作，
eventually it just I think it breaks
最终我认为它坏了
down at a point and certainly we're
下降一点，当然我们是
doing something as important as a
做一件重要的事
specification I think tracking the
我认为跟踪规范
history tracking the changes tracking
历史跟踪更改跟踪
who's making that you know very
谁让你很了解
persistently and very easily using
持久且非常容易使用
well-known and established tools is
众所周知的成熟工具是
really important and I know frankly I do
真的很重要，我坦白地知道
everything in asciidoc would get so that
asciidoc中的一切都会变得如此
with my recommendation don't just use
我的建议不只是使用
HTML that's just wrong the best Jenner
最好的Jenner错的HTML
in California sunny we're ok can you
在加利福尼亚州晴，我们可以吗
hear me like the wife has not fast I
听到我像老婆还没斋戒我
mean you know conference but getting
表示您知道会议，但越来越
ready for the phase like 10 a.m. and
准备好像上午10点和
yeah a lot of a lot of Java in Jakarta
是的，雅加达有很多Java
II
II
knowledge going on here in the sessions
在会议上进行的知识
so that's bigger one and yeah greetings
所以这是更大的，是的问候
greetings from San Francisco they could
来自旧金山的问候，他们可以
so what put feelings or sentiments did
那么感受或情感的表现
you catch with respect to Jakarta II
你就雅加达二世着迷
actually a lot going off for both
实际上两者都有很多
Jakarta and and micro profiles so you
雅加达和微型配置文件让您
definitely can see that that this is
绝对可以看到，这是
advancing and that people are you know
前进，你知道的人
enthusiastic about it or in in other
对此或其他方面充满热情
words like if you know if you talk about
像你知道是否谈论的话
enterprise Java then it's you know here
企业Java那么您就在这里
from content-wise mostly either Jakarta
从内容上讲，大多数是雅加达
or micro profile or both which i think
或微轮廓或两者兼而有之
is good and there's also quite quite a
是很好的，还有一个相当
bit going on of that in combination with
与之结合的一点点
new cloud native technology like how to
新的云原生技术，例如如何
do that with kubernetes how to do that
用kubernetes做到这一点
with this do which i think is a part of
我认为这是其中一部分
the positive development yeah so would
积极的发展是的
you see that right so maybe for parts of
您看到的是正确的，所以也许对于
it but I would rather see it as
它，但我宁愿将其视为
complementing rather than replacing
补充而非替代
because if you go to like Java eight
因为如果你喜欢Java 8
point of view right now right there not
观点现在就在那里
many features that really you know
您确实知道的许多功能
collide collide with with is geo in
与发生碰撞
terms of resiliency or in terms of
弹性或
traffic management or things like that
交通管理或类似的事情
right so I think that's actually a
对，所以我认为这实际上是
compliment compliment cherries delusion
恭维樱桃妄想
to use both and to use you know plain
既使用又使用就知道
Java EE even in this do actually that's
Java EE即使在这种情况下实际上也是如此
that's what I showcased in one of my
这就是我在其中之一中展示的
sessions which I think makes a lot of
我认为很多会议
sense to combine these things and then
感觉结合这些东西，然后
you know how I see personally is that
你知道我个人的看法是
and then you know developments involve
然后你知道发展涉及
involvements that now happen in micro
现在发生在微观
profile basically compliment and fill
简介基本上是恭维和填补
the gaps what is still needed so for
差距仍然需要什么
example open tracing right if you want
示例公开跟踪权，如果您想
to do tracing with micro services and do
用微服务进行跟踪并做
that with an is do you still for example
那个是你还在吗
need to pass the HTTP headers you know
需要传递您知道的HTTP标头
any examples like that way just like
像这样的任何例子
fill in the gaps
填补差距
same for observability right you just
对于可观察性也是一样
make it accessible whatever happens only
使无论发生什么都可以访问
output and that is done in a no standard
输出，这是没有标准的
like fashion be it with micro profile
像时尚一样，具有微轮廓
order and later on hopefully with
订购，以后希望与
jacquard EE that gets incorporated and
提花EE并入
then this was just the attitude II
那只是态度二
applications but for my point of view
应用程序，但以我的观点
like the programming model and the
如编程模型和
deployment
部署
it makes a lot of sense to make that in
使其具有很大的意义
a similar way like we had in a Java EE
就像我们在Java EE中一样
world right X in deployment artifacts
部署工件中的世界X
that run on a runtime that then mate
在随后匹配的运行时上运行
might be also you know support for
也许您也知道支持
example micro profile I'm showcasing a
我正在展示的示例微资料
lot of open Liberty and just deploying
很多开放的自由，只是部署
Java EE applications right that might be
Java EE应用程序可能正确
enhanced with micro profile and
通过微轮廓和
recording guy in the room just stopped
房间里的录音人刚停下来
him when the session started to get
会议开始时他
interesting the missing bits I'm not
有趣的是我不是缺少的部分
sure so III did our presentation it was
可以肯定的是III做了我们的介绍
recorded did get some good comments back
记录确实得到了一些好评
from it and what I was trying to do was
从中，我想做的是
talk about the relationship current and
谈论当前的关系和
future between Jakarta EE and micro
雅加达EE和micro之间的未来
profile I wrote a blog about this couple
我写了一篇关于这对夫妻的博客
I don't know a couple months ago now and
我几个月前不知道
that's what I ended up doing is kind of
我最终要做的是
reactivating that blog as a presentation
重新激活该博客作为演示文稿
and that's what I brought forward
这就是我提出的
granted I mean it was it was my opinion
当然，这是我的意见
of what you know how these things are
你知道这些事情如何
going to be working together but I
要一起工作，但我
thought it was very good that you asked
以为你问的很好
Mike the question and to see what his
迈克的问题，看看他的
answer was and I was very consistent I
答案是，我非常一致
think everybody is you know we've made a
认为每个人都是您知道我们已经做了
lot of progress with micah profile
micah配置文件取得很大进展
there's no reason to just say oh stop
没有理由只说哦停止
work on that and let's move on jakarta
为此工作，让我们继续雅加达
ee i mean it wouldn't wouldn't be right
EE，我的意思是那不会不对
and so at some point we will want to
所以在某个时候我们会想要
move some of these technologies into
将其中一些技术转移到
jakarta ee but it's not going to be an
雅加达ee，但不会成为
overnight thing though I don't know was
一夜之间的事情，虽然我不知道是
there something specific when you said
你说的话有些特别
that I was I stopped or I felt like it's
我曾经停下来，或者我觉得
a bit of a cliffhanger so you presented
有点悬念，所以你介绍了
the two projects and and then it was a
这两个项目，然后是一个
cliffhanger that
那个
what now but obviously we no one has the
现在发生了什么，但显然我们没有人
answer
回答
yet so it has to be a cliffhanger I
但它一定是我的绝壁
personally think also at some point in
我个人也认为
time it makes a lot of sense to sort of
时间很有意义
merge micro profile into Java EE and
将微型配置文件合并到Java EE中
have that let's say as an incubator
可以说是一个孵化器
where we can keep the speed of
在这里我们可以保持速度
innovation as a micro profile with the
创新是微观的
possibility to break things if we find
如果我们发现有可能破坏事物
out it doesn't work for our users that
出来对我们的用户不起作用
we change an API or we we change
我们更改API或更改
semantics or whatnot and then after a
语义或其他什么，然后
few releases when we say okay now it's
当我们说好的现在很少发布
stable it's only minor Corrections then
稳定的话，那只是轻微的改正
it's promoted to standout spec final
晋升为最终杰出规格
whatever it's called and then going in
不管叫什么然后进去
the let's say slower Jakarta slower but
可以说，雅加达慢一点，但是
more stable Jakarta track it smiling why
更稳定的雅加达跟踪它微笑的原因
is that just because I'm happy
是因为我很开心
nice to be here so I'm a peer I'm
很高兴来到这里，所以我是同龄人
smiling so I think it was much worse if
微笑，所以我认为如果
I was not smiling right so sleeping or
我没有微笑，所以睡觉或
you know like so much I'm smiling it
你知道我这么微笑
means that I like it everything that
意味着我喜欢一切
Michael is dealing a good job in making
迈克尔在制作方面做得很好
ap is making specifications which is
ap正在制定规格
really needed for micro services
微服务确实需要
development for cloud development and
云开发和
this is one of the reasons why we are
这是我们之所以的原因之一
supporting this API is in project
在项目中支持此API
halidom we support in wonderful ami P is
我们在精彩的ami P中支持的万圣节是
the moment where we are that's
我们在那里的那一刻
previously we are supporting almost one
以前我们支持几乎一个
or two it guys we're missing only GW j
一个或两个家伙，我们只想念GW j
JW I said I'm happy
我说我很高兴
J WTF missing and micro portal is the
J WTF丢失，微门户网站是
really deal in a great doing the great
真正做到一件大事
work right so about joining Jakarta now
正确地工作，以便现在就加入雅加达
at some point it will happen because
在某个时候会发生，因为
Jakarta is the standard deviation field
雅加达是标准偏差字段
right my proposal is not a standard as
是的，我的建议不是一个标准
you said incubate
你说孵化
okay so and I remember them when Jakarta
好吧，我记得他们在雅加达
I II know II forge a project was
我II知道II建立了一个项目
starting and one of their statement the
开始和他们的陈述之一
air force we would like to have micro
我们想拥有的空军
profile right so it's going on what came
配置文件正确，所以发生了什么
in said it's going on so it's going on
在说它正在进行，所以它正在进行
yeah I'm coming my Tina caller with
是的，我要跟我的Tina来电
Fujitsu and everything the challenge
富士通和一切挑战
that we see for for Jakarta E is cadence
我们为雅加达E看到的是节奏
the downfall of of Java okay nobody ever
Java的衰落好吗没人
had a problem with Java the gun you know
Java有问题，您知道这把枪
multi millions of users but when Java
数百万的用户，但是当Java
releases started stretching out and
发布开始扩展，
stretching out okay then the language
伸出好然后语言
the customers found other ways to get
客户找到了其他获取途径
things done to keep their technology's
为保持技术水平所做的事情
current there was two years from Java EE
目前距Java EE已有两年时间
7 to Java EE eight okay we cannot allow
7到Java EE八行，我们不允许
that to be the situation for Jakarta
这就是雅加达的情况
Oracle has addressed that the Java SE
Oracle已解决Java SE
thing by taking and announcing six-month
并宣布六个月
release cycles for SE micro profile I
SE micro profile I的发布周期
believe is moving into a Jakarta
相信正在进入雅加达
it's been a year now we've got to get
一年过去了，我们必须
that out but once we get it out we've
出来，但是一旦我们拿出来，我们已经
got to get in on a cadence which is melt
必须融入节奏
up multiple times a year okay so that we
一年好几次，这样我们
can keep it they lively and and current
可以保持它们活跃和最新
technology fully agree and I believe
技术完全同意，我相信
that if you have a cadence quick cadence
如果你有一个节奏，那么快速节奏
it also doesn't matter
没关系
much if one of the sub specifications
如果子规范之一
misses the release because the next one
错过了发布，因为下一个
is to follow quickly and so we don't
是要迅速跟进，所以我们不
have to delay the whole release brain
必须延迟整个大脑的释放
for this one sub specification I would
对于这一子规范，我会
like to mention that technical vision
喜欢提及技术远景
document again I already mentioned that
我再次提到文件
the beginning of this meeting through
通过会议开始
disco dance is a part of that as well so
迪斯科舞也是其中的一部分
this is what a technical vision document
这是技术远景文件
basis what pmc sees as technical
PMC认为技术性的依据
direction which they put foj project
他们把项目的方向
will take and dance was interesting what
会跳舞，跳舞很有趣
else is there you can find it on e4 j
否则你可以在e4 j上找到它
official website as suppose we have been
假设我们一直在官方网站
talking about working groups and PMC and
谈论工作组和PMC，以及
foj and so on for those who are not that
foj等，对于那些不是那样的人
familiar with it perhaps later Wayne
也许以后会熟悉韦恩
could you give a quick overview what
您能否简要概述一下
these individuals things are and what I
这些人的事情是什么，我
mean okay first off I guess I should
好的，首先我想我应该
point out that the Eclipse Foundation
指出Eclipse Foundation
has been doing a simultaneous release
一直在同步发布
now of like 80 projects very long time
现在有80个项目，时间很长
in let's go and we've just recently
走吧，我们最近
switched to doing the release we've been
切换到发布我们一直在发布的版本
doing for more than a decade now doing
现在做了十多年
it four times a year don't
一年四次
anyway get keen on that so some of the
无论如何，请对此保持热衷
terms PMC project management committee
条款PMC项目管理委员会
is that is that the level you you asked
那就是你要求的水平
okay so so PMC's are a project level
好的，所以PMC是项目级别的
construct so we have a notion of a top
构造，所以我们有一个顶级的概念
level project that provides governance
提供治理的高级项目
and oversight and they they do things
和监督，他们做事
like they're part of the intellectual
就像他们是知识分子的一部分
property processing process for the or
或的财产处理流程
the projects under their umbrella so the
在他们的保护下的项目，所以
top level project organizes a collection
顶级项目组织收藏
of open-source projects and again
开源项目
provides basically their that they're
基本上提供他们的
the the the primary first level of
主要的第一级
governance for that governance and
该治理的治理和
management for that project a part of me
该项目的管理是我的一部分
within a project we have committers
在一个项目中，我们有提交者
Tomatoes are the individuals who have
西红柿是
the ability to actually make
真正的能力
contributions a project has a project
一个项目有一个项目
lead project leads more of less
牵头项目牵头少
responsive us about power more about
回应我们有关权力的更多信息
responsibility project leads are the
责任项目负责人是
primary interface between the project
项目之间的主要接口
and well me I represent I'm basically
好吧，我代表我基本上是
the the front the front door I guess of
我猜的前门
the e mo which is the Eclipse management
e emo是Eclipse管理
organization the Eclipse management
组织Eclipse管理
organization is actually comprised of
组织实际上是由
the Eclipse architecture Council the
Eclipse体系结构委员会
Eclipse Planning Council the staff of
Eclipse规划委员会的工作人员
the Eclipse Foundation and the executive
Eclipse基金会和执行官
director of course and I act as the face
导演当然是我的脸
of that for for projects so everything
对于项目来说，这一切
I've said right now is really all about
我说过，现在真的是关于
collaborating developers collaborating
合作开发者合作
together so committers work with
一起使提交者与
contributors managing contributions to
贡献者管理对
projects that sort of thing again that's
再次投射那种东西是
all about you know developers
关于您的一切都认识开发人员
collaborating working groups I shall
我将合作的工作组
might be inclined to pass to Paul our
可能倾向于将保罗交给我们
more about organizations collaborate and
有关组织合作的更多信息以及
I think with that I will try not to
我认为我会尽量不要
stumble through an answer and I'll send
偶然发现一个答案，我会发送
it to the expert where we're expert
交给我们专家的专家
means I know a little bit more than you
意味着我比你了解更多
right is that how that goes so working
正确的是，如何运作
groups are a construct that we've added
组是我们添加的构造
to the Eclipse Foundation to essentially
到Eclipse基金会
allow businesses to define the
允许企业定义
governance rules for how they interact
互动规则
with each other
彼此
so in the same way that projects are
所以就像项目是
fairly well understood we have an
相当了解，我们有一个
eclipse development process and all the
蚀发展过程和所有
way inside about the pmc defines how
关于pmc的内部定义方式
that's done at the software level but
这是在软件级别完成的，但是
for this to work the companies that are
为此工作的公司
working together also need to have
一起工作也需要
similar rules for how they engage who's
他们如何与谁互动的类似规则
permitted to do what who's expected to
被允许做谁期望的事情
do what and so on and so at a very
做某事等等等等
simple level a working group is just an
简单的水平，一个工作组只是一个
agreement amongst those companies who
这些公司之间的协议
are participating in how they're going
参与他们的发展
to engage and so the basic tool that we
参与，所以我们的基本工具
use for describing that is that is the
用于描述那是
working group Charter so projects have a
工作组宪章，使项目有一个
Charter EMC has a Charter
宪章EMC拥有宪章
top-level project has a Charter and and
顶级项目有一个章程，以及
so a working group has a charter so if
所以一个工作组有一个章程，所以如果
you if you go to the Jakarta EE website
如果您访问Jakarta EE网站，则为您
you'll find a link there to the Charter
您会在此处找到《宪章》的链接
and it defines how each of those
它定义了每个
companies are going to interact and so
公司将进行互动，因此
through that Charter we've talked
通过该宪章，我们谈到了
already about the steering committee and
已经有指导委员会了，
the spec committee and America ting
规格委员会和美国庭
committee and so on well all of those
委员会等等所有这些
constructs are defined within the
构造在
Charter and what they're there their
宪章及其在那里的存在
obligations are are also defined in the
义务也定义在
Charter and so we also define you know
宪章，所以我们也定义您知道
the various levels of participation that
不同程度的参与
we talk about the strategic members and
我们谈论战略成员
you've heard a lot about their activity
您听说过很多关于他们的活动
but there's also 15 or so participant
但也有15位左右的参与者
member companies who are involved in
参与的会员公司
this and they have a role to play within
这并在其中发挥作用
within the working group as well and
在工作组中
rights obligations and so on we also
权利义务等等，我们也
have committee members so eclipse has
有委员会成员，所以日食有
this very we think fairly unique idea
这就是我们认为相当独特的想法
that our committers are also part of the
我们的提交者也是
overall foundation right so in the same
整体基础也一样
way that member companies are
成员公司的方式
participate and and are part of the
参与，并且是
overall agreement with each other
彼此达成总体协议
members sorry committers also have that
成员对不起提交者也有
that right and so all of those
那个权利等等
constructs are defined within the
构造在
working and so the relationship between
工作之间的关系
the working group and in this case the
工作组，在这种情况下
Jakarta working group and those projects
雅加达工作组和那些项目
is in many ways orthogonal
在许多方面是正交的
right there is no it's not that the
对，没有，不是
working groups elv the projects you have
工作小组负责您拥有的项目
to do this and it's not like the
做到这一点，这不像
projects can tell the working groups
项目可以告诉工作组
this is what has to happen it is we
这是必须发生的事情，是我们
think a very pragmatic approach to
认为一个非常实用的方法
recognizing that there are business
认识到有生意
interests and the business of Jakarta
兴趣和雅加达业务
needs to get done right we need to
需要做正确的事，我们需要
promote the brand we need to work on
推广我们需要努力的品牌
these specifications to find the rules
这些规范找到规则
for how that engages the IP flows all of
关于如何吸引IP流
those things are in many ways business
这些事情在很多方面都与生意有关
issues and so that influences the
问题，因此影响
projects but it doesn't necessarily
项目，但不一定
control it and vice versa
控制它，反之亦然
right the things that the projects are
正确的项目是
doing they they are independent they
做他们他们是独立的他们
have the rights to do certain things
有权做某些事情
they can they can act in the best
他们可以做到最好
interest of the project and the
项目的利益和
committers are those who make the
提交者是那些使
decisions within the projects but there
项目内的决定，但在那里
is a reality that you know the business
是您了解业务的现实
interest is play a role and so it is not
兴趣在发挥作用，因此不是
a hard-and-fast one governs the other
坚强的人统治另一个
it's it's it's just each of them does
就是每个人都做
the things recognizing the other side
认识另一面的事物
exists and being responsive to those and
存在并响应那些
and and and you know our experience has
并且，而且您知道我们的经验
been that that actually works very well
一直以来都很好
there are well what happens if you can't
如果你做不到，那会发生什么
resolve things well we we actually tried
解决问题，我们实际上尝试过
to define in the guidelines in the
在指南中定义
Charter and ultimately in our bylaws in
宪章，最终在我们的章程中
terms of what we're the final decisions
我们最终决定的条款
why but you know Mike would if he were
为什么，但是你知道迈克会不会
here would be telling you in his 14
这将在他的14中告诉你
years or so running the foundation we've
多年经营我们的基础
never really had to get to there's a
从来没有真正去过那里
dispute that couldn't be solved so we
争议无法解决，所以我们
find it a very pragmatic approach that
发现它是一种非常实用的方法
actually is pretty successful tutorial
其实是相当成功的教程
but just the same it's a question that
但同样是一个问题
we come across very often and it's not
我们经常碰到，不是
an easy thing to explain going back to
一件很容易解释的事情
marketing again I think Stephanie she's
我认为她是斯蒂芬妮
running the newsletter and some some
运行时事通讯和一些
webinars about stuff so if someone on
关于内容的在线讲座，因此如果有人
the screen at home now thinks that's a
家里的屏幕现在认为这是一个
good idea I want to write something or
好主意，我想写点东西或
even present something what could they
甚至提出一些东西，他们可以
do
做
email me is the simplest approach I
给我发电子邮件是我最简单的方法
suppose so essentially what I do is like
假设我所做的基本上就是
he said runs the newsletter currently in
他说现在正在运行时事通讯
a couple months it will be our new
几个月，这将是我们的新
marketing as well I do the virtual
营销我也做虚拟
Eclipse community meetups which our
我们的Eclipse社区聚会
webinars hosted at the foundation on
基金会举办的网络研讨会
YouTube live streamed so we want to
YouTube直播了，所以我们想
encourage people to participate show
鼓励人们参加表演
their demos of what they're working on
他们正在工作的演示
for clips technologies as well as new
剪辑技术以及新技术
releases new things about a project that
发布有关项目的新事物
is interesting and share it with the
很有趣，并与
community so yes and I also run all the
社区，是的，我也经营
social media so if you ever want a blog
社交媒体，因此，如果您想要博客
posted either on our website or on the
张贴在我们的网站或
jacquard EEE website or social media or
提花EEE网站或社交媒体或
just helping push community outreach
只是帮助推动社区拓展
again definitely send me an email
再次肯定给我发电子邮件
Daphne dot Swart SW arity at eclipse -
蚀的达芙妮·斯威特（Daphne）
foundation org and I'll get it done for
基金会组织，我将完成它
you thank you more questions
你谢谢你更多的问题
contributions answers new projects to
捐款回答新项目
start ok here one question regarding the
从这里开始，关于
relation to micro profile what I noticed
我注意到的与微轮廓的关系
this Michael profile started out as
Michael的个人资料最初是
framework supporting micro services a
支持微服务的框架
lot of things which I could also apply
我也可以运用很多东西
to enterprise applications are kind of
企业应用程序是
kind of supporting
某种支持
something like this that you see more of
这样的事情，您会看到更多
this frame were parts like recently it
这个框架像最近一样
was configuration for example for Wi-Fi
是用于Wi-Fi的配置
as well
以及
which was integrated and I think a lot
这是整合的，我认为很多
of the things like Jesus thing would be
像耶稣这样的事情
the rest client and maybe some other
其余的客户，也许还有其他
things like traceability could also
诸如可追溯性之类的事情也可以
apply to to normal web applications it
适用于普通的Web应用程序
was something planned to get this more
计划要得到更多
together was it still that it's like
还是在一起，就像
separate that it's only usable in this
分开它仅在此可用
micro-services approach and not in the
微服务方法而不是
normal enterprise both that Jakarta is
雅加达既是普通企业
hurting I give it to Kevin and I said
伤了我给凯文，我说
yeah because I think it applies to any
是的，因为我认为这适用于任何
vendor if I understand the question
供应商，如果我理解这个问题
correctly you're seeing some advantages
正确地，您看到一些好处
to the Micah profile
到Micah个人资料
components or pieces of the programming
编程的组成部分
model and how could it apply to an
模型以及如何将其应用于
application server in general and and I
应用服务器一般和我
think that's that's what we're seen and
认为那就是我们所看到的
you mentioned you you mentioned you know
你提到你你提到你知道
open Liberty are the WebSphere Liberty
开放的自由是WebSphere自由
and that isn't it an example it's not
那不是一个例子，不是
that the micro micro profile doesn't
微观轮廓不
mean you have to have a micro
意味着你必须有一个微型
application server you know so you can
您知道应用服务器，因此您可以
build upon it I was talking was a
在此基础上，我正在谈论的是
persistence layer defined from micro
从微观定义的持久层
profile and it has been brought up we've
个人资料，并已提出，我们已经
talked about it with the community and
与社区讨论过
it's basically because not one size fits
基本上是因为没有一种尺寸适合
all so maybe some micro services need
所以也许有些微服务需要
relational databases some need no SQL
关系数据库有些不需要SQL
maybe some just a caching the
也许有些只是缓存
distributed caching network is
分布式缓存网络是
sufficient and so it's not that we are
足够，所以这不是我们
just trying to limit the component
只是试图限制组件
of like your profile that that's all
就像您的个人资料一样
that you would ever need but you may
您将永远需要，但您可能
need other aspects of an application
需要应用程序的其他方面
server to solve the problems that you're
服务器来解决您所遇到的问题
looking for so I and I know that you
寻找所以我，我知道你
know wildfly or authority all is in the
知道野蝇或权威都在
same boat no yeah so I mean we started
同一艘船不，所以我是说我们开始了
with the whole market profile I thought
我认为整个市场概况
on what it what what's what what was
关于什么是什么
called wild fly swarm which is now farm
叫做野蝇群，现在是农场
tail and then we have just seen that
尾巴，然后我们刚刚看到
things are working nicely like the
事情像
configuration API which is also nowadays
当今的配置API
are so that others had the same idea
这样其他人也有相同的想法
right
对
so we said for for plain wild fly why
所以我们说对于普通的野蝇
should we not just take that and and
我们不应该只是接受而
have a unified approach so that we can
有一个统一的方法，以便我们可以
use that all over the place because it
在各处使用它，因为它
makes sense and use these additional
有意义并使用这些额外的
config sources like reading from a
配置源，例如从
kubernetes config map and make it
kubernetes配置图并使其
available to all these products or
适用于所有这些产品或
talking of observability which is
谈论可观察性是
monitoring tracing and so on I mean this
监视跟踪等等，我的意思是
is monotone is a bit of a pet peeve of
是单调的，有点像宠物
mine right but we have done that at work
我的权利，但我们已经在工作中做到了
in micro profile there is still more
在微观方面，还有更多
work to be done but it has shown
工作要做，但已经表明
successful it's working it's finally a
成功工作了，终于
unified way of getting monitoring data
统一获取监控数据的方式
out of the server I mean yes there is
在服务器外面，我的意思是，有
JMX but this always had its contact
JMX，但这总是有联系
specialties and then there's also the
特色菜，然后还有
world has evolved with monitoring
监控不断发展
systems like Prometheus or influx DB
Prometheus或Influx DB等系统
that did not exist at a time where Jim
在吉姆的时代不存在
jmx was a thing for reading of data
jmx是用于读取数据的东西
right so we also said well it's it's
对，所以我们也说是
it's working nicely in infante so why
它在婴儿方面运行良好，为什么
don't we just use it in whitefly where
我们不只是在粉虱中使用它吗
we have the same need right
我们有同样的需求
yes because as you mentioned micro
是的，因为您提到微
profile which are not yet though it is
个人资料虽然还不是
indeed a good idea to combine those and
结合这些确实是一个好主意，
a lot of vendors doing it your muir fir
很多供应商都在做你的缪尔杉木
mentioned the most of them payara is
提到他们中大多数
also one of them that we are explicitly
我们明确地也是其中之一
working to combine those because it
努力将它们结合起来，因为它
helps I guess almost all people that you
帮助我猜猜几乎所有人
also have those microphones available I
也有那些麦克风我
pass the mic to Tommy tribe it was not
将麦克风传递给汤米部落，那不是
from what I know planned that we will
根据我所知道的计划，我们将
migrate this stuff over into world fly
把这些东西迁移到世界苍蝇
but it's rather that it has just shown
而是它只是显示了
successful so that we say ok let's use
成功，所以我们说好吧，让我们使用
it yeah i Bernard I like how that it's
是的，我伯纳德，我喜欢那是怎么回事
you know these technologies are
你知道这些技术是
obviously useful in minimal application
在最少的应用中显然很有用
service but also in your sort of
服务，但也要您
full-blown application servers as well
完善的应用服务器
so it's not a surprising and quite
所以这并不奇怪
encouraging to see these make these
鼓励看到这些使这些
features making their way through the
功能正在通过
larger application servers as well
更大的应用服务器
I kind of understand the things you are
我有点了解你的事
saying I have just one small tiny
说我只有一个小小的
problem with that that we are breaking
我们正在打破的问题
portability of applications and that's
应用程序的可移植性
one of the things that Jakarta even
雅加达甚至做过的一件事
though we didn't release for a very long
虽然我们很久没发布
time was kind of a good ad and by
时间是一种很好的广告
introducing nice micro prospects which I
介绍我很好的微观前景
agree are really needed we have a
同意真的需要我们有一个
problem or customers because if you use
问题或客户，因为如果您使用
one application server with one metric
一台具有一个指标的应用程序服务器
version you will not deploy anywhere
您将不会在任何地方部署的版本
else so like the basic idea of Java EE
否则就像Java EE的基本思想
and Jakarta is kind of broken with this
雅加达对此有点不满
it's just a concern that I see you know
我知道你只是担心而已
I understand why it's happening on the
我了解为什么它会在
other hand I think that there is a
另一方面，我认为有一个
danger in there I mean micro profiles
那里的危险，我的意思是微观轮廓
solid with with the premise of being
以存在为前提
able to make these breaking changes I
能够做出这些重大改变
totally value what you say and having a
完全珍惜您所说的话，并且拥有
stable API over years or stable metric
多年来稳定的API或稳定的指标
output and all these things it's also a
输出和所有这些东西也是
bit problematic because very often you
有点问题，因为很多时候你
can only get feedback if people really
只有当人们真的
use it in real scenarios and then they
在实际场景中使用它，然后他们
figure out what works what doesn't work
弄清楚什么有效，什么无效
and give you feedback and then you can
并给您反馈，然后您就可以
you improve on it and it's it's at the
您对此有所改善，这是在
worst case it may mean that you need to
最坏的情况可能意味着您需要
break a compatibility
破坏兼容性
what I was trying to say is I don't have
我想说的是我没有
a problem is micro profile and if you
问题是微观档案，如果您
build a micro service on micro profile
在微概要文件上构建微服务
that's absolutely fine and you have a
那绝对很好，你有一个
single micro service that you have you
您拥有的单个微服务
know on a single version of an
知道一个版本
application server my problem was with
应用服务器我的问题是
porting micro profile specifications
移植微型配置文件规格
into Jakarta or Java EE application
进入Jakarta或Java EE应用程序
servers where you are you know like the
您所处的服务器就像
Mel that we talked about here before
梅尔，我们之前在这里谈论过
that you kind of think yeah this is a
你以为是的，这是一个
great idea but once you import it into
好主意，但是一旦将其导入
your java application suddenly you are
您的Java应用程式突然间
creating that application bound to that
创建绑定到该应用程序
version of server and that's much bigger
服务器版本，并且更大
scope because micro services with micro
范围，因为微服务与微
profile that's you know small part
您知道的个人资料很少
enterprise java application that's a big
企业Java应用程序很大
thing you know breaking compatibility
你知道破坏兼容性的事情
there is more important completely you
完全重要的是你
are not forced you are not forced to use
不被迫不被迫使用
the micro profile api's in a java ee
Java EE中的微型配置文件api
server that also has to make a profile
还必须进行配置文件的服务器
stuff something to me means that I'm
给我一些东西意味着我
ready to Java upon on an IBM product and
准备在IBM产品上使用Java并
I can move it to write a product that's
我可以移动它来写一个
portable and they're both certified on
便携式，并且都通过了认证
the same micro profile doesn't guarantee
相同的微轮廓并不能保证
backward compatibility because
向后兼容，因为
innovation is keys is the main one of
创新是关键之一
the main goals
主要目标
whereas Jakarta EE I'm assuming that
而Jakarta EE我以为
just like Java EE has this you know
就像Java EE拥有这个一样
mission of being back or attempting to
回来或试图做的任务
be back we're compatible
回来我们兼容
right I have a question in Jakarta
对，我在雅加达有一个问题
yee-aw Java EE we have the TCK that
是的Java EE，我们有TCK
insurance portability so in micro
保险的便携性
profile is there also one TCK
个人资料中也有一个TCK
specification yeah okay you take
规格是的，你可以
I'm not sure take on what I just heard
我不确定我刚才听到的
the question about the TCK sorry I'm
关于TCK的问题抱歉，我是
drawing a blank
画一个空白
I mean I know we we've kind of talked
我的意思是我知道我们已经聊过
about it I guess I don't I don't have
关于它，我想我没有，我没有
anything else to add
其他要添加的内容
okay what else someone on line
好吧，还有谁在线上
I saw someone called at once no probably
我看到有人立刻打来电话
at some sessions that one
在某些会议上
not having nice beer because so early
没有这么好的啤酒，因为这么早
for them Tori
为他们托里
yes there's a question and another
是的，有一个问题，另一个
question in another domain currently
当前在另一个域中的问题
according to my observation the
根据我的观察
developers attention is on cloud
开发人员的注意力在云上
platform and in particular on kubernetes
平台，尤其是在kubernetes上
and their attention it there for the
和他们在那里的关注
moment and I have observed that it is
片刻，我观察到
very difficult to present them and to
很难呈现给他们
gain attention on Jakarta and even micro
引起人们对雅加达甚至微型汽车的关注
profile because their focus is in
简介，因为他们专注于
another place so they they have for
另一个地方，所以他们有
instance they use other frameworks
实例他们使用其他框架
there are well-established framework for
有完善的框架
cloud native applications and I wonder
云原生应用程序，我不知道
how to address
如何解决
I hope self a gap between these kind of
我希望自我之间的差距
events but if you participate to local
活动，但如果您参加本地活动
organizations very much difficult
组织非常困难
because ok people most of them are using
因为好吧，大多数人都在使用
spraying or Nadya's or whatever and from
喷涂或Nadya或其他
it's a difficulty when I try to to
当我尝试去
convince people
说服人们
about the the interest of this
关于这个的利益
technology I I wonder if this is a
技术二想知道这是否是
specific observation or I have no
具体观察还是我没有
solution for that but I think it's very
解决方案，但我认为这非常
important to find a way to get the
重要的是找到一种方法来获得
proper attention to Reno not an easy
适当注意里诺并非易事
question
题
you're absolutely very hard to get this
你绝对很难得到这个
mind share or mind share back
心灵分享或心灵分享
I mean Jakarta Java EE was a real thing
我的意思是Jakarta Java EE是真实的东西
a few years five and JPA and egb three
几年5和JPA和egb 3
it grew a lot again because impulse from
它又增长了很多，因为来自
the outside which also was spring at
外面也是春天
that time interestingly enough and then
那个时候足够有趣，然后
I think the gap between EE 7 and ee 8
我认为EE 7和EE 8之间的差距
was so long that people lost a little
这么久，人们失去了一点
bit track and there was all these things
位跟踪，所有这些东西
doc are coming along and then later
doc来了，然后再来
kubernetes it was not foreseen and and
kubernetes，这是不可预见的，并且
then there is a little bit of an overall
然后有一点整体
perception problem I mean not now but
感知问题，我不是现在，而是
not too long ago when I was talking
不久前我在讲话
about people with Java they were like oh
关于使用Java的人，他们就像哦
it's it's slow I tried it on what Java
这是很慢的我尝试了什么Java
SE one one it was slow so it's slow
SE一一慢，所以慢
right and of course I think the best
对的，当然我认为最好
thing is really we all go out to our
真的是我们全都出去
local jerk or remote Chuck whatever in
本地混蛋或偏僻的查克
the next big city and just talk about
下一个大城市，然后谈论
these things with Jakarta
这些东西与雅加达
of course it's much more problematic
当然有很多问题
because there is not much to show yet
因为还没什么要展示的
but this will be better once GlassFish
但这一旦GlassFish会更好
will be released or charged Jakarta ie
将被释放或指控雅加达
comfortable right so there is something
很舒服，所以有东西
to show around and then the other
展示周围，然后另一个
windows will also come with their
窗户也将与他们一起
releases sooner or later and then you
迟早发布，然后您
can really show and then so I did on
可以真正显示，然后我做了
Monday
星期一
on the community day I did a little bit
在社区日，我做了一点
of a workshop hands-on with micro
微型研讨会的动手实践
profile and we have some very nice
个人资料，我们有一些非常好的
things in there for example with the
那里的东西，例如
rest client you have a back-end service
休息客户，您有一个后端服务
you take the interface file put two
你把接口文件放两个
annotations in the right place and then
注释在正确的位置，然后
you can just call out without any effort
你可以毫不费力地喊出来
right this is the power that we need to
对，这就是我们需要的力量
go out and show to people and say look
出去向人们展示并说看
you can get running very quickly and
您可以非常快速地运行，
then with the right runtime which is
然后在正确的运行时
also not too fat I mean also spring has
也不太胖，我的意思是春天也有
to bring a JVM right I mean that that
使JVM正确我的意思是
part is when we start up quickly and
部分是当我们快速启动时
have this very quick get going with all
有这么快的一切
these nice things then I think we can
这些好东西，我想我们可以
also get my ok ok doesn't look like we
也可以，我看起来还不错
need to market the hell out of it so we
需要推销它，所以我们
we will not we we can help but we are
我们不会，我们可以提供帮助，但我们是
not you are not writing the content
不是你不是在写内容
correct ok we also need the content and
正确，我们还需要内容
one thing that would help is the the
一件事会有所帮助的是
experience of getting started right
正确入门的经验
micro profile and where we are on it
微观概况以及我们所处的位置
we're working on it right now and Rudy
我们正在努力，而鲁迪
is right here and she's she I'm sorry to
就在这里，她是她，我很抱歉
one too many beers yeah he he's put
啤酒太多了，他放了
together a a wizard driven user
一起是向导驱动的用户
experience to basically you can you know
经验，基本上你可以知道
navigate through a couple of windows and
浏览几个窗口，然后
select what micro profile API you want
选择您想要的微配置文件API
and also select the implementation that
并选择实现
you want and it'll generate
您想要的它将生成
a set of artifacts that you basically
基本上是一组工件
and then sample code for you to get
然后为您提供示例代码
started and we're gonna be calling that
开始了，我们会打电话给
start on micro profile or IO and that's
从微型配置文件或IO开始，那就是
in the works already the the merge the
在作品中已经合并了
merch happen already right but we
商品已经发生了，但是我们
already merge his code into the project
已经将他的代码合并到项目中
and the next step is going to be
下一步将是
actually the Eclipse Foundation is going
实际上，Eclipse Foundation正在
to provide the infrastructure to run
提供运行的基础设施
that on and then the next step is to
然后，下一步是
reskin available for developers to go
可供开发人员使用的Reskin
and start using it right so that I can
并开始正确使用它，以便我可以
you can exploit that in your meetings
您可以在会议中利用它
with with your folks the jugs and and
与您的人们一起壶和
the next thing on the plate is we have
盘子里的下一件事是
code samples we have actually a we
我们实际上有一个代码样本
already have a directory with samples
已经有样本目录
but it's a bit outdated and plus there
但是有点过时了
there are other samples that different
还有其他样本不同
people have micro profile samples
人们有微轮廓样本
sitting in different repositories at
坐在不同的存储库中
this point and and that's the next thing
这一点，这是下一步
we're gonna do is we're gonna
我们要做的是
rationalize that and reorganize it and
合理化并重组
put it in where the samples live now so
放到现在有样品的地方
that you know it'll be another resource
你知道这将是另一种资源
for developers to get started quickly
让开发人员快速入门
using microphone I think I think that's
使用麦克风，我想我认为是
very important to have this kind of
拥有这种
experience for the developers because
开发者的经验，因为
lots of the mindshare the frameworks you
很多人分享您的框架
mentioned also comes from the fact that
提到的原因还在于
one single developer can just take the
一个开发人员可以
framework on the web and quickly prepare
网络上的框架并快速准备
a quick and dirty version to show to
快速而肮脏的版本显示给
their management and babies and okay oh
他们的管理和婴儿，好吧哦
that works so let's continue with that I
那行得通，所以让我们继续
think that maybe the next step is there
认为下一步可能在那里
so one of those frameworks I know in
所以我所知道的那些框架之一
France is a shape stare or Jeepster I
法国是一个形状凝视或吉普车我
don't know
不知道
oh you are you from that so the bit of
哦，你来自那个，所以
scaffolding and though on the on the
脚手架，虽然在
generated application I don't know how
生成的应用程序我不知道
far is your without going but if if at
远就是你不走，但如果在
some point there is the idea to put just
有些观点是有想法
a bit of scaffolding and and user
脚手架和用户
experience in the generated code that's
在生成的代码方面的经验
that that's also something that could be
那也可能是
passing interesting the ability to
通过有趣的能力
quickly start the project and to
快速启动项目并
showcase something also in France at
在法国也展示一些东西
least in France tipster is very popular
至少在法国Tipster很受欢迎
and I wonder if it would be possible to
我想知道是否有可能
generate micro profile back ender for
生成微型配置文件背面渲染器
instance because it's tough welding so
实例，因为它很难焊接
it may be possible and Jeepster is
有可能，而吉普车是
adopted by many many developers because
被许多开发人员采用，因为
it enables to start a web project very
它可以启动一个Web项目
quickly so this is a suggestion I had
很快，所以这是我的建议
also in mind we did we didn't discuss
还记得我们没有讨论
before but I - I fully agree though
之前但我-我完全同意
maybe we getting we can get in touch
也许我们能取得联系
with the Jeepster project and see you
与Jeepster项目一起见
there feeling about that the other
那里的另一种感觉
interesting aspect but I'm not
有趣的方面，但我不是
completely sure if it's an advantage or
完全确定这是一个优势还是
burden is that once people start using
负担是一旦人们开始使用
Takada ie again they can also reuse
高田即再次他们也可以重复使用
their previous knowledge of Java Java EE
他们以前对Java的了解Java EE
because there are still parts left from
因为还有剩余的零件
that time that I can still use like JPA
那时我仍然可以像JPA那样使用
for persistence for example I mean you
为了坚持，例如我是说你
get that for free between quotes because
在报价之间免费获得它，因为
it's just part of Jakarta II anything
它只是雅加达二世的一部分
else
其他
though here on the remote a little any
虽然在遥控器上有点
questions don't be shy
问题不要害羞
they're shy okay I mean if there's
他们害羞好吧，我的意思是如果有
nothing more then I want to thank you
仅此而已，我要谢谢你
all for participating here I hope there
我都希望参加这里
is still some cold beverage left over in
还剩下一些冷饮
the other room and enjoy the remainder
另一个房间，享受其余的
of the conference and just to say
会议的目的，只是说
everyone I need to recognize fabulous
我需要认识的每个人都很棒
I'm seeing from Waco and keeping you all
我在Waco见面，让你们所有人
engaged and thank you for the feedback
参与，并感谢您的反馈
and of course please find a way to
当然，请找到一种方法
participate into the Jakarta world and
参加雅加达世界，
spread the news engage developers and
传播新闻，吸引开发商
keep in touch okay thanks thank you
保持联系好，谢谢
young
年轻